<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<article id="index">
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Get Hot New Stuff Specification</title>
    <releaseinfo>Version 0.1</releaseinfo>
    <date>29 April 2005</date>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<firstname>Josef</firstname>
	<surname>Spillner</surname>
	<affiliation>
	  <address>
	    <email>spillner@kde.org</email>
	  </address>
	</affiliation>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="overview">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>
    Desktop applications today are either working with data files or can be enhanced
    by them, or both. The interchange of those files between users of said applications
    is however not standardised. This specification covers a way to let users upload and
    download their data files and thus share them with each other.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="storage">
    <title>A unified scheme for data sharing</title>
    <para>
    Based on the existing GHNS ("Get Hot New Stuff") framework, which exists with
    implementations for KDE and SDL, and the XML format used for downloads of
    AGO (art.gnome.org), a unified, generic sharing framework is proposed to be
    implemented by all free desktops.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="providers">
    <title>Providers</title>
    <para>
    In order to find a place to host files and download files from,
    a directory service-like request is done first. This is implemented
    by a so-called provider resource, an XML file which lists all of
    the available providers with its upload and download URLs, icon,
    web access URL and (internationalised) name.
    Not all of thoese attributes have to be given, it is however recommended
    to implement all of them to achieve a higher usability.
    </para>
    <para>
    See the appendix 'Provider DTD' for more details.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="upload">
    <title>Upload format</title>
    <para>
    Upload data includes information about authorship (author name
    and email), the data part itself (payload, preview and summary)
    as well as meta information: version, release number, release
    date and license.
    </para>
    <para>
    See the appendix 'Upload DTD' for more details.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="download">
    <title>Download format</title>
    <para>
    In the download specification both the meta data given by the
    author of the contribution and the data aggregated by the web server
    is contained. One such file may list one or more items.
    </para>
    <para>
    See the appendix 'Download DTD' for more details.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="metadata">
    <title>Meta-data</title>
    <para>
    The rating is a value between 0 and 100, with 0 meaning lowest and
    100 meaning highest level of appreciation.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="stufftypes">
    <title>Data item types</title>
    <para>
    Every data item is assigned a specific type.
    How those are related to MIME types will be shown here.
    </para>
    <para>
    desktop/wallpaper - ???
    kdeedu/vocabularies - ???
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="licenses">
    <title>Licenses</title>
    <para>
    The following license abbreviations are recognised and be linked
    to automatically. If another license is chosen, the URL to the
    text should be given and the license abbreviation field should
    be left empty.
    </para>
    <para>
    gpl - GNU General Public License
    bsd - BSD-style license
    publicdomain - Works in the public domain
    ...
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <appendix id="changes">
    <title>Change history</title>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.1, 29 April 2005, Josef Spillner</title>
      <para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Initial draft specification. Takes into account the existing
	      software and practice from KNewStuff and art.gnome.org.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
  </appendix>
</article>
